

# Eng. Maikel Barrios Insua

# Summary

Full-stack developer with over 7 years of experience in Golang, Python, and TypeScript. Proficient in developing a wide range of applications from Single Page Applications (SPA) to e-commerce platforms. Strong database skills with MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB. Experienced with frameworks such as FastAPI, Fiber (Golang), GORM, Django-restframework, Next.js 13, Vue.js, and Angular. High problem-solving capabilities.

### **Skills**

- Programming Languages: Golang, Python, TypeScript
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Frameworks: FastAPI, Fiber (Golang), GORM, Django-restframework, Next.js 13, Vue.js, Angular
- Problem-solving
- English (Advanced)
- Spanish (Native)
- > Tailwind, Bootstrap, Vuetify 3, Flowbite
- Vitest, Selenium, Jest, Fiber test, Playwright
- Docker, Redis, Git, GitHub Actions.
- Linux CLI, AWS, Azure.

### **Experience**

#### \*\*Full-Stack Developer\*\* | Free Lance | 2016 - Present

- > Developed and maintained various web applications, including SPA and e-commerce platforms.
- Worked with a variety of databases including MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB to store and manage data.
- Utilized various frameworks such as FastAPI, Fiber (Golang), GORM, Django-restframework, Next.js 13, Vue.js, and Angular to build robust and scalable applications.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Continuously discovered, evaluated, and implemented new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

#### \*\*Front-end Developer\*\* | 2Innovate | 2023 - Present

- Frame Banking platform UI application interface development using Vue3.
- Configuration and hosting with dockers containers
- ➤ I used AWS services for hosting services
- Configuration and use of Oracle, MySQL and PostgreSQL

#### \*\*Full-Stack Developer\*\* | Ledefyl | 2022 - 2023

- I developed and fixed applications oriented to network monitoring
- > I worked with javascript libraries like React and frameworks like Angular.
- Microservices with Django-Rest and Flask
- Database with MySQL
- Server configuration (Nginx)
- Quality Testing

#### \*\*Web Master\*\* | Ministry for Science Technology an Environment | 2022 - 2023

- Penetration testing
- Website quality test
- Functional test
- Integration test
- Development of measures of quality, and efficiency of the software life cycle

### \*\*Network Engineer\*\* | Technological University of Havana Cuba | 2019 - 2021

- Design and configuration of highly scalable networks
- Configuration of server (Apache, Nginx)
- Working with the most demanded network protocols

#### \*\*Telematics Technician\*\* | Telecommunication Company of Cuba | 2007 - 2014

- > Installation and maintenance of data network equipment
- Cabling and configuration of network cards

## **Education**

- Telecommunications and electronics engineer
- Technological university of Havana Jose Antonio Echeverria Bianchi, cuba junio 2021

## **Best Project**

- Migration from Senchajs to Vue3 of the location card console in the 2Innovate company
- Creation of an online store with Go(Fiber, Gorm), Nextjs 13, Vue3 and MySQL
- Migration of application infrastructure in the Ledefyl company.

# **Contact Information**

- > email://ingmbi8807@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/mbi-bi/
- https://github.com/MBI-88
- https://api.whatsapp.com/send?phone=59891359503
- Uruguay Montevideo

## References

- Omar Antonio Hernandez Duany. Main professor of programming at Jose Antonio Echeverria Cuaje, Cuba Computer Engineer. <a href="mailto:oahd1963@gmail.com">mailto:oahd1963@gmail.com</a>
- Niurka Armas. Ministry of Science, Technology and Environment CITMA, Cuba Department Director. <a href="mailto:niurka.armas@citma.gob.cu">emailto:niurka.armas@citma.gob.cu</a>